<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.lullabyX.sone</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <name>SONE</name>
  <summary>Native Linux client for TIDAL — lossless and bit-perfect audio streaming</summary>

  <developer id="io.github.lullabyX">
    <name>Hassan Rabbi</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>Stream your TIDAL library in lossless FLAC and Hi-Res quality up to
       24-bit/192kHz — with the option to bypass your system mixer entirely
       for bit-perfect output.</p>
    <p>A familiar, modern interface inspired by the streaming apps you already use.
       Exclusive ALSA mode bypasses PulseAudio and PipeWire entirely, sending
       the unaltered signal directly to your DAC for bit-perfect playback.
       Or use normal mode for casual listening through your system's default output.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Lossless FLAC and Hi-Res streaming up to 24-bit/192kHz</li>
      <li>Exclusive ALSA output for bit-perfect streaming to USB DACs</li>
      <li>Volume normalization (ReplayGain) with automatic album/track switching</li>
      <li>Scrobble to Last.fm, Libre.fm, and ListenBrainz with ISRC and MusicBrainz metadata</li>
      <li>Synced lyrics display</li>
      <li>Custom themes with full color picker</li>
      <li>Queue persistence across restarts</li>
      <li>MPRIS media controls and system tray</li>
      <li>Proxy support — route traffic through HTTP, HTTPS, or SOCKS5 proxies</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Unofficial client — requires an active TIDAL subscription. SONE is a
       streaming client only and does not support offline downloads.</p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.lullabyX.sone.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/lullabyX/sone</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/lullabyX/sone/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/lullabyX/sone</url>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#FDF2F8</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#31274F</color>
  </branding>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lullabyX/sone/master/data/sone_drawer_metainfo.png</image>
      <caption>Now playing drawer with synced lyrics</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lullabyX/sone/master/data/sone_homepage_metainfo.png</image>
      <caption>Home page with TIDAL streaming library</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lullabyX/sone/master/data/sone_search_metainfo.png</image>
      <caption>Search and explore</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lullabyX/sone/master/data/sone_theme_metainfo.png</image>
      <caption>Custom theme with full color customization</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <video container="webm" codec="av1" width="1920" height="1080">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lullabyX/sone/master/data/sone_demo_metainfo.webm</video>
      <caption>SONE in action</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2026-03-09">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>HTTP, HTTPS, and SOCKS5 proxy support with a new settings UI — all traffic routes through your configured proxy</li>
          <li>Exclusive mode now probes your DAC's supported formats and sample rates, avoiding mismatches and falling back gracefully</li>
          <li>Toast notifications when exclusive mode resamples audio or encounters unsupported sample rates</li>
          <li>Playback stops cleanly on network errors instead of draining the queue, with user-friendly error toasts</li>
          <li>ALSA writer respawns on device change — hot-swapping DACs no longer requires a restart</li>
          <li>Tray icon and global shortcuts no longer prevent startup if unsupported</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2026-03-07">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Scrobble your listening history to Last.fm, Libre.fm, and ListenBrainz — complete with ISRC and MusicBrainz metadata</li>
          <li>Toggle window decorations to switch between native and custom title bar</li>
          <li>Repeat and shuffle now work correctly — wrap-around, repeat-one, and shuffle-aware playback all fixed</li>
          <li>Fixed rapid track skipping causing the UI to freeze</li>
          <li>User menu reorganized into clean, grouped sections</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
